A Guide to the Asia Society photographs and special formats FA105
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Audiovisual materials, 1
  - Tassilo Adam films, bulk; 49 Film Reels Tassilo Adam film collection encompasses approximately 25,000 feet of film on 49 reels. The collection includes 35 negatives and 14 prints in 16mm and 35mm formats.
    - Awakening, Silent, Black and white, 13 minutes. Condition is okay. There are some splices and a slight odor but fine to project.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white positive, 470 feet. (Reel AV 2276)
      Scenes of city life including automobiles driving down city streets, a parrot eating corn, man with pet baboon trained to knock coconuts off of trees, man in a field exercising and people rowing canoes down a river. Additional footage of Lembak people of Indonesia watering animals, playing in water, woman combing each others' hair, village life and people walking down city streets.
      IV 3B6 f 40
    - Java Roll 3, Silent, Black and white, 29 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white negative, 1034 feet. (Reel AV 2277)
      Reel includes Asia Roll 9, Java Roll 10, 11, 12. Asia Roll 9 includes scenes of musicans playing instruments, warriors dancing and Indonesia horse dance. Java Roll 10 includes parade footage,and a wayang performance accompanied with gamelan orchestra. Java Roll 11 includes scenes of a parade, village life and open market. Java Roll 12 contains scenes of Javanese coast and men bringing a boat into the water.
      IV 3B6 f 41
    - Boli, Silent, Black and white, 9 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white positive, 325 feet. (Reel AV 2345)
      Ceremonial dance in costume (masks, dragon), without costume/female in costume/musicans/male in costume (mask and robes)/group of dancers (masks and robes), close-ups/warriors dancing (ceremonial)/ ceremonial fingernails on female/cockfight. Footage of men hydrating and keeping cool.
      IV 3B6 Fb 4
    - Bodoyo Dancers II, Silent, Black and white, 6 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is poor. film is starting to warp and is shrunken. Do not project.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white positive, 225 feet. (Reel AV 2344)
      Large temple - looks like Buddnist/musicans, group of female court dancers.
      IV 3B6 Fb 5
    - Bodoyo Dancers I, Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is okay. There is a film puncture through te first half.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white positive, 366 feet. (Reel AV 2343)
      Group of female court dancers, large temple and court musicans. Intertitle cards in Dutch.
      IV 3B6 Fb 6
    - Isle Bali 2, Silent, Black and white, 3 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is okay. The film is begining to warp and may be slightly shrunken.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white positive, 129 feet. (Reel AV 2342)
      Footage of man and boy's faces acknowledging the camera. Westerns being greeted, female court dancers, sword handles, faces, shrines, view of countryside, shrine, cockfight.
      IV 3B6 Fb 8
    - Markets - Streets, Silent, Black and white, 3 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white positive, 121 feet. (Reel AV 2341)
      Footage of men women and children walking through the streets acknowledging the camera, cooking in the market, purchasing hats, baskets and portable water jugs. Intertitle cards in Dutch.
    - Crafts, Silent, Black and white, 7 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good. There are many splices.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white positive, 267 feet. (Reel AV 2340)
      Footage of brass production, a few scenes of wood carving. Film is erratically spliced with many duplicate scenes. Intertitle cards in Dutch.
      IV 3B6 Fb 12
    - Bull Races, Silent, Black and white, 6 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; Footage of festivals, dancing, important people leaving in automobiles and shaking hands with others outside, arrival by car to the bull racing festivals, and bull's decorations.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white positive, 233 feet. (Reel AV 2339)
      IV 3B6 Fb 11
    - Farmers, Silent, Black and white, 12 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white positive, 465 feet. (Reel AV 2338)
      FOOTAGE OF PLOWING WITH OXEN IN RICE PADDIES; VIEW OF RICE TERRACES; RICE PLANTING; RICE HARVESTING; OX CARTS TRANSPORTING RICE; CUTTING SUGAR CANE.
      IV 3B6 Fb 1
    - Calebese, Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white positive, 395 feet. (Reel AV 2337)
      Map showing trip and stops. Welcome arch. People lined up waving, dances (warriors), parade, island views, waterfalls, harbor, passenger liner at dock, "mansion", old fort, temple, speed boat, shoreline, cliffs, ceremonial dance, and village market. Footage of fruit gathering and women opening up fruit. Canoes in water and villagers paddling in canoes.
      IV 3B6 Fb 2
    - Dutch Ship, Silent, Black and white, 8 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white positive, 300 feet. (Reel AV 2346)
      Footage of Harbor scenes, small sailing craft, barges, passengers debarking, women carrying their babies, rickshaws and city scenes.
      IV 3B6 Fb 10
    - Tassilo Adam film II, Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is poor. There is lots of edge damage.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white positive, 400 feet. (Reel AV 2347)
  - Wedding Ceremony of Indrawati Roosheroe and Nondon Gandjar, Silent, Black and white, 10 minutes. Available in 16mm. Condition is good; slight odor.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white positive, 365 feet. (Reel AV 2288)
    Islamic marriage ceremony of Indonesian Ambassador Dr. Sunario's ward Indrawati Roosheroe to engineer Nondon Gandjar, at the Ambassador's residence in Hampstead London, England in 1959. Scenes of people congratulating the bride and groom, having refreshments outside, ceremonial dance of two women performed in traditional attire, bride feeding her groom with a small ball of rice and tradition of foot washing is performed.
    IV 3B6 f 12
  - Silla's Twin Timulus - Northern Tomb, Sound, Color, 53 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is okay, slight odor and color has faded.; 16mm acetate film base, color positive, 1928 feet. (Reel AV 2287A, Reel AV 2287B)
    A film produced by the Korean Film Unit in 1975 of the excavation of the Northern Tomb in Silla, one of the three ancient kingdoms of Korea. The film showcases historical archaeology of Korea, ancient burial practices, excavating artifacts such as bronzeware, pottery, jewerly and royal crowns. The cleaning and preservation practices of the archeologists is emphasized.
    IV 3B6 f 13a and IV 3B6 f 13b
  - Archaeology in Thailand, Sound, Color, 31 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is okay. The color has faded.; 16mm acetate film base, color positive, 1121 feet. (Reel AV 2294)
    Documentary film about archaeology in Thailand with a focus on the 1966 excavation of the Ban Chiang archaeology site. Narrated by Vidya Intakosai and Produced by Dhanit Yupho.
    IV 3B6 f 14
  - Wayang Kulit (the Shadow Puppet Theatre of Java), 1970; Sound, Color, 22 minutes. Avaiable on 16mm. Condition is okay. There is a slight odor and color has faded to red.; 16mm acetate film base, color positive, 770 feet. (Reel AV 2292)
    A visual exploration of Wayang Kulit, the shadow puppet theater of Indonesia. A documentary showing scenes from an all-night performance of wayang kulit play, with behind-the-scene views of the dalang (puppeteer) manipulating the puppets as well as views from the audience side of the screen. Includes demonstration of how a puppet is carved and explanation of its characteristics and a showcase of a gamelan orchestra. Narrator, Murati Waghudi; puppeteer, Dalang, Oemartopo; gamelan, Kyai Kumbal. Produced and directed by Baylis Glascock. Copyright 1970, Samuel H. Scripps Inc.
    IV 3B6 f 15
  - Challenge of Change, 1961; Sound, Color, 18 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is okay. There is a slight odor and the color has faded.; 16mm acetate film base, color positive, 639 feet. (Reel AV 2304)
    A 1961 dramatization presented by Bell Systems on the future of technology and telecommunications. The film breaks into two parts. Part I: the problems of the present, and part II: the way those problems could be solved by the technology of the future. Technology presented in this film include wireless Bellboy Pager, the Data-phone, videophone, card-reading phone or automatic dialer, and drone delivery systems via rocket. Written by Jerome Alden, produced by Henry Strauss and directed by Robert Wilmot. Copyright 1961, American Telephone and Telegraph Company.
    IV 3B6 f 16
  - Lee Graham Interviews: on Asia Society, 1964; Sound, Black and white, 15 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is okay. There is vinegar syndrome.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white positive. (Reel AV 2305)
    A program from UHF New York City Channel 31 Lee Graham Interviews. First segment: Lee Graham interviews the executive director of the Asia Society Paul C. Sherbert regarding the historical background, mission and educational purposes of the Asia Society. Second segment: A South Indian Napalese dance is performance. Third segment: Lee Graham interviews Virginia Field, assistant director to the Art Gallery at Asia House discusses art exhibitions and Asian artists.
    IV 3B6 f 17
  - Asia Society, WNET, 1981; Silent, Color, 11 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is okay, color has faded to red.; 16mm acetate film base, color positive, 411 feet. (Reel AV 2286)
    Footage of New York City and Asia Socety's headquarters at Park Avenue and East 70th Street on the Upper East Side. Incudes shots of the Asia Society's engravings in the smooth red granite stone and a miniature of the building.
    IV 3B6 f 45
  - Asia Society Fair, Silent, Color, 10 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is okay. Film smells of vinegar syndrome with many splices on one side.; 16mm acetate film base, color positive/color reversal/work print, 374 feet. (Reel AV 2293)
    Footage of Asia Society Fair at the Asia Society's New York headquarters. Includes scenes of musicans, vendors with jewelry, masks and fabrics, food, dancers, karate and stick fighting.
    IV 3B6 f 47
  - Mission to Yeman, 1944; Silent, Black and white, 21 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good. There is a slight odor.; 16mm acetate film base, black and white positive, 775 feet. (Reel AV 2289)
    A 1944 film produced by John Ford of the wartime mission to the Chinese Communists in their headquarters. Shot by OSS operatives in wartime China, this is the story of their visit to Chinese cCommunist headquarters in Japanese-occupied China during World War II. Features Mao Tze-Dung, Cho En-lai.
    IV 3B6 f 43
  - Ground Breaking Ceremony (NEG), 1978; Silent, Color, 10 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good. There is a slight odor.; 16mm acetate film base, color negative, 390 feet. (Reel AV 2284)
    Footage of ground breaking ceremony in 1978 of where the Asia Society's headquarters in New York City would be built. Includes crowd scenes, cityscapes, people making speeches and an Indonesian female dancer performing a traditional dance.
    IV 3B6 f 44
  - Ground Breaking Ceremony (WORKPRINT), 1978; Silent, Color, 10 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is okay; slight vinegar syndrome and color has faded to red.; 16mm acetate film base, color positive, 390 feet. (Reel AV 2285)
  - An Interview with Indira Gandhi, 1975; Sound, Color, 28 minutes. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm polyester film base, color positive, 1023 feet. (Reel AV 1781)
    FROM A CANADIAN NEWS SOURCE, A PROFILE OF INDIAN PRIME MINISTER INDIRA GANDHI. SHOWN AT WORK AND AT HOME, THE EPISODE DISCUSSES GANDHI'S CAREER AND CURRENT STRUGGLES WITH POWER, AMIDST A STATE OF EMERGENCY AND ACCUSATIONS OF TYRANNY. DIRECTED AND PRODUCED BY PAUL SALTZMAN; A SUNRISE FILMS LTD PRODUCTION (1975)
    IV 3B6 f 46
  - Chess, Sound, Color, 30 seconds. Available on 16mm. Condition is good.; 16mm acetate film base, color positive, 32 feet. (Reel AV 2252)
    30 second TV publuic service spot promoting volunteer recruitment for the Mayor's Voluntary Action Center.
    IV 3B6 f1 / RG 1.3 BOX 49 FOLDER 352 N.Y.C. Voluntary Action Corp.
- China - Chu Fu and Khyber Pass
- Kashmir
- Unidentified
- China - Great Wall and Peking
- Canadian Rockies, Hawaii, Korea and Japan
- Hawaii and Japan
- Chitar and Hang Chow
- Japan
- Japanese Literature
- China - Peking
- Unidentified Slides
- Korea
- Unidentified Slides (Box 13, Box 11, Box 12, Box 9, Box 10, Box 7, Box 8, Box 6, Box 5, Box 4, Box 3, Box 2, Box 1, Box 14)